<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<doc>
<title>Math.RandomGenerator class</title>

<para>
<ptitle>Math.RandomGenerator class</ptitle>
　Math.RandomGenerator is a class for generating random numbers by the <at href="http://www.math.keio.ac.jp/~matumoto/emt.html" target="_blank">Mersenne Twister</at> method.<r/><r/>
　The syntax of the constructor is as follows.
<bq>
new Math.RandomGenerator([&lt;Random seed>]);<r/>
</bq>
<r/>
　Specifying a number in the constructor initializes the random number generator with that number.<r />
　If you specify a dictionary array object that saves its state with the serialize method in the constructor, you can create a random number generator in that state.<r />
　If the constructor is omitted, the random number generator is initialized with a random value based on the current time. (In the case of Kirikiri 2, it is initialized with a random number from the random number generator based on environmental noise instead of the current time. ).<r />
</para>

<para>
<ptitle>randomize</ptitle>
　The randomize method initializes a random number generator. The arguments are the same as those specified in the constructor.<r/>
</para>

<para>
<ptitle>random</ptitle>
　The random method returns a real random value between 0 and 1.0.<r/>
</para>

<para>
<ptitle>random32</ptitle>
　The random32 method returns an integer random value between 0 and 4,294,967,295 or less (0xffffffff or less).<r/>
</para>

<para>
<ptitle>random63</ptitle>
　The random63 method returns an integer random value between 0 and 9,223,372,036,854,775,807 (0x7fffffffffffffffff or less).<r/>
</para>


<para>
<ptitle>random64</ptitle>
　The random64 method returns an integer random value between -9,223,372,036,854,775,808 and 9,223,372,036,854,775,807.<r/>
</para>

<para>
<ptitle>serialize</ptitle>
　The serialize method returns a dictionary array object that records the current state. This dictionary array object can be reproduced again by passing it to the constructor and randomize method.<r />
</para>

<para>
<ptitle>Copyright notice</ptitle>
　To implement the Mersenne Twister method<r/>
<r/>
   A C-program for MT19937, with initialization improved 2002/2/10.
   Coded by Takuji Nishimura and Makoto Matsumoto.<r/>
<r/>
　The modified version is used. Thanks to both for releasing useful program sources.<r />
<r />
   Copyright (C) 1997 - 2002, Makoto Matsumoto and Takuji Nishimura,<r/>
   All rights reserved.<r/>
<r/>
   Redistribution and use in source and binary forms, with or without<r/>
   modification, are permitted provided that the following conditions<r/>
   are met:<r/>
<r/>
	 1. Redistributions of source code must retain the above copyright<r/>
		notice, this list of conditions and the following disclaimer.<r/>
<r/>
	 2. Redistributions in binary form must reproduce the above copyright<r/>
		notice, this list of conditions and the following disclaimer in the<r/>
		documentation and/or other materials provided with the distribution.<r/>
<r/>
	 3. The names of its contributors may not be used to endorse or promote <r/>
		products derived from this software without specific prior written <r/>
		permission.<r/>
<r/>
   THIS SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED BY THE COPYRIGHT HOLDERS AND CONTRIBUTORS<r/>
   "AS IS" AND ANY EXPRESS OR IMPLIED WARRANTIES, INCLUDING, BUT NOT<r/>
   LIMITED TO, THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR<r/>
   A PARTICULAR PURPOSE ARE DISCLAIMED.	 IN NO EVENT SHALL THE COPYRIGHT OWNER OR<r/>
   CONTRIBUTORS BE LIABLE FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL,<r/>
   EXEMPLARY, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES (INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO,<r/>
   PROCUREMENT OF SUBSTITUTE GOODS OR SERVICES; LOSS OF USE, DATA, OR<r/>
   PROFITS; OR BUSINESS INTERRUPTION) HOWEVER CAUSED AND ON ANY THEORY OF<r/>
   LIABILITY, WHETHER IN CONTRACT, STRICT LIABILITY, OR TORT (INCLUDING<r/>
   NEGLIGENCE OR OTHERWISE) ARISING IN ANY WAY OUT OF THE USE OF THIS<r/>
   SOFTWARE, EVEN IF ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGE.<r/>
<r/>
</para>


</doc>

